CANDIDATENAME	ANDREW A OKOLO		
CURRENT JOB TITLE:	Chief Business Strategies	Contact:	+2348035066325,
			+2348129423013.
	Self employed.		+2348070791501
			E-Mail -
			ikouredo@gmail.com

Andrew Okolo, is a graduate of Marketing from Ramat Polytechnic Maiduguri, Postgraduate Diploma in marketing from University of Maiduguri, Postgraduate diploma in Education, Sir Kashim College of Education Maiduguri, Master Degree in Industrial and Labour Relation from University of Maiduguri.

He is an energetic sales and management Specialist with 18 years in Sales operation and management, Sales and operation management, with a track record of continuous improvement in simplifying route to market and Market

activation, salessupportfunctions in a high volume outlets and cluster formulation, customer focused with the ability to resolve complex sales strategy, exceptionally proficient in managing day to day scheduling and calendar management duties. Andrew is qualified to serve as liaison with internal and external agencies, works as a team and autonomously; guaranteeing to create a climate that foster growth and development and deeply familiar with Microsoft word, Excel, PowerPoint, SAP ERP and adapt quickly to new programs. I fix what bugs me in a system!

Andrew worked in the easy buy sales in Sunking solar, green light planet previously and currently work as Chief Business Strategist at Kinjapaul Venture, one of the off grid solar provider for off grid. Due to constant improvement of sales performance across the region, he was promoted from Sales manager to Regional sales and now the Chief Strategist.

His achievement ranges from

- Route to market alignment from B2B, B2C, creating more selling outlet which increase company sales from 52% to 76% within the region .
- (HGMM)Hellenic good morning meeting with team by7.00am to7.30am, helping in reviewing team performance leading to increase in performance by 25% compared to previous day.
- Timely payment of rebate to dealers, promoters and vendors within the region, quarterly reconciliation, and sales team management.
- Initiated complaint hotline for swift response to customers resolution on product availability,
 SKU availability and new product penetration and feedback from sales team and customers.
- Supervised sales team on selling skills, new product development, product cycle, motivation, coaching and product handling, this giving overview of 21% increase on turn around supply index
- Trained, supervised, and appraised about 27 hired staff, providing undivided attentive support to co-workers which increase overall efficiency by 30%

• Opex management, cost per case with this we save 19% of the budget.

NATIONALITY:	Nigerian	CURRENTLOCATION:	Abuja, Nigeria
INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE	Sales Strategy, Commercial Business Development	AVAILABILITY:	2 Weeks
EMPLOYEMENT TYPE	Permanent	EMPLOYMENT STATUS:	Full-Time
DESIRED SALARY:	Based on negotiations	Managed Others:	Yes

QUALIFICATIONS

Master's Degree-industrial and labour relations(MILR), *University of Maiduguri* Postgraduate diploma in Education.(PGDED) *Sir Kashim College of Education, Maiduguri* Postgraduate Diploma in Marketing(PGDM), *University of Maiduguri*. Higher National Diploma in Marketing(HND) 2002, *Ramat Polytechnic, Maiduguri* National Diploma in Business Studies(OND), *Kogi State Polytechnic, Lokoja*

ANDREW A. OKOLO

PROFILE

An adept business and sales manager with 18 years of professional experience in leading the implementation of business growth strategies, driving sales representatives and sales managers, ensuring revenue increase, optimizing business plans and processes, and ensuring improved customer service delivery. Identifies new market and business potentials, leading sales managers, and team to close out new leads and potentials.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

- Business Analysis and Development
- Strategic Planning and Organization
- Business and Commercial Leadership
- Business-2-Business Management
- Financial Management.
- Account management
- Contract Management
- Stakeholder Management
- Persuasive Selling Skills

- Driving Operational Effectiveness
- Performance Management
- Pipeline Management
- Route-to-Market Strategy Design
- Vendor Management
- Commercial Sales & Business Strategy
- Cross-functional Team Management & Development
- Territory and Regional Management

EDUCATION

Master's Degree-industrial and labour relations(MILR) *University of Maiduguri*

Postgraduate diploma in Education.(PGDED) Sir Kashim College of Education, Maiduguri

Postgraduate Diploma in Marketing(PGDM) *University of Maiduquri.*

Higher National Diploma in Marketing(HND)2002 Ramat Polytechnic, Maiduguri

National Diploma in Business Studies(OND) Kogi State Polytechnic, Lokoja

Community Secondary School, Ugwolawo Kogi State.

TRAINING ATTENDED

- Sales Academy Training
- Industrial Training
- Leadership Pipeline
- Category Management
- Passion to Lead
- Basic Selling Skills

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Chief Business Strategist Kinjapaul Venture-Abuja, Northern Region Nigeria August 2022 – Present

- Day to day operation of the company ,close monitoring of Sales within the region.
- Recruiting of sales operation team, motivation, coaching and training of regional team.
- Opex monitoring to achieve profitability of the Organization.
- Route to market alignment to increase sales

Regional Sales and Operation Manager. Kadick Integrated limited – South-South Warri Nigeria October 2020 – August

2022

- Provide correct input into the compilation of the company's vision.
- Developing and implement sales profitability plans according to account management principlesthat
- Ensure the development and maintenance of account plan.
- Coordinate daily regional operations with Head of finance operations.
- Recruitment of Retail Sales Supervisor, Inventory manager, Shop Executives, Business Manager etc.
- Activation of market to look of success.
- Training and retraining of regional sales team.

Regional Sales Manager Tolaram Group of Company–North-West, KanoNigeria April 2020 – September 2020

- Monitoring of area sales managers towards achieving of their daily targets, also initiated daily tracking form which led to volume growth from 120 daily sales to 560 daily.
- Planned and implemented market activation leading to sales growth,
 volume growth and awareness creation which gave us volume growth of 50% incremental.

Regional Business Manager Green light planet(Sunking) –North-East, Gombe, Nigeria May 2018 – August 2019

- Achieve Easy Buy Direct and Retail Sales revenue targets.
- Ensure daily, Weekly, Monthly, Quarterly and Yearly reports are accurate and submitted within agreed timelines.

Strategic planning

- Proper Management of default rates to agreeable set limits by overseeing quality customer registration, collection, and repossession.
- Regional Team Management-Recruitment and retention of regional sales teams through training management.
- Proper recruitment of teams following set guidelines and policies by GLPHR.
- Maintain optimum regional headcount as agreed from time to time.

Trade management

• Develop and propose incentives to motivate the channel and Team to ensure high levels of motivation and performance.

Develop and implement action plans for trade with clear corrective measure where required. Ensure that all competitor activities are counterwith effective responses to avoid oss of market share.

 Ensure Visibility in the trade is high and as per agreed picture of success at all outlets.

- Nurturing of Direct Reports and resources assigned to self.
- Ensure that all cost and expenses are kept within acceptable levels and within budget.

Simba Group of company –Assistant Branch Manager Northeast ,Yola Nigeria 2017-2018

- Retail expansion through appointment and management of distributors to drive product penetration and achieve both horizontal and vertical growth.
- Meet regional sales financial objectives by forecasting requirements; repairing budget; analyzing variances and initiating corrective actions.
- Accomplish regional sales human resource objectives by recruiting, selecting, orienting, training, assigning, scheduling, coaching, counseling, and disciplining employees in assigned districts, communicating job expectations; planning, monitoring, appraising, and reviewing job contributions; planning and reviewing compensation actions; enforcing policies and procedures.
- Expand retail outlet base by counseling Area Sales Executives, building and maintaining rap pore with key retail outlets, identifying new customer opportunities.
- Accomplish sales and organization mission by completing related results as needed. Ensure that all cost and expenses are kept within acceptable levels and within budget.

Regional Sales Manager-Yola Commercial Territory & Maiduguri NBC PLC 2007–2017

- Maintained sustainable and productive relationships with existing clients.
- Managed daily operations, including employee training and development, contract negotiations, and production planning.
- Assessed risks involved with new initiatives, ensure deadlines are met and be ready to handle unexpected situations.
- Identified opportunities to expand the business through partnerships, mergers, and new markets.
- Analyzed sales, marketing, finance and other reports, improved performance, and maximized growth.
- Developed accurate and consistent bids with the help of relevant departments.
- Identifiedopportunitiestoexpandthebusinessthroughpartnerships,mergers,and new markets.
- Analyzed sales, marketing, finance and other reports, improved performance,

- and maximized growth.
- Developed accurate and consistent bids with the help of relevant departments.
- Maintained sustainable and productive relationships with existing clients.
- Managed daily operations, including employee training and development, contract negotiations and production planning.
- Assessed risks involved with new initiatives, ensure deadlines are met and be ready to handle unexpected situations.

Senior Corporate Sales Manager Starcomms plc-North East, Maiduguri Nigeria. 2004 - 2007

- Achieved sales growth and hit sales targets by successfully managing the sales team.
- Designed and implemented strategic business plan and expanded company's customer base.
- Oversaw recruiting, KPI's creation, coaching, and performance monitoring of sales team.
- Build and promoted strong, long-lasting customer relationships and increased market base.
 - Present sales, revenue and expenses reports and realistic forecasts to the management
- Identified emerging markets.

Marketing Manager S and S Wireless-North East Maiduguri, Nigeria 2003 - 2004

- Motivate staff and led the team to achieve sales targets.
- Interviewed and selected new members of the sales team.
- Carried out sales training with sales executives and role-playing sales techniques.
- Set sales targets and activity key performance indicators.
- Reported on progress towards sales KPI's.

Liaised with other departments within the company.